<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Github on Tek Shinobi Blog</title>
    <link>https://tek-shinobi.github.io/categories/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Github on Tek Shinobi Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 19:53:20 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tek-shinobi.github.io/categories/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Github:managing Multiple Accounts: SSH configuration</title>
      <link>https://tek-shinobi.github.io/posts/github_managing-multiple-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 19:53:20 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tek-shinobi.github.io/posts/github_managing-multiple-accounts/</guid>
      <description>Notes for SSH key configuration with multiple Github accounts.&#xA;I have multiple github accounts. Say one for work and one that is personal.&#xA;NOTE: This logic can be extended to more than two accounts.&#xA;The setup can be done in 5 easy steps:&#xA;Steps: Step 1 : Create SSH keys for all accounts Step 2 : Add SSH keys to SSH Agent Step 3 : Add SSH public key to the Github Step 4 : Create a Config File and Make Host Entries Step 5 : Clone GitHub repositories using different accounts OR modify remote url for existing repos Step 1 Create SSH keys for all accounts First make sure your current directory is your .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Add Gpg Keys to Repo</title>
      <link>https://tek-shinobi.github.io/posts/add-gpg-keys-to-repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 22:53:11 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tek-shinobi.github.io/posts/add-gpg-keys-to-repo/</guid>
      <description>Add GPG keys to github repo and local The process involves a set of simple steps:&#xA;Create GPG keys from commandline terminal Export the created keys using armor into a text blob. Take the blob and head over to github account -&amp;gt; Settings -&amp;gt; SSH and GPG keys and add it as GPG key The most important point: cd to you local repo directory and configure the key there. This step will need to be done for every local repo.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
